ariix.com 2019-05-23

# Privacy Policy - ARIIX - The Opportunity Company

ARIIX Privacy Policy effective May 25, 2018. ARIIX, its affiliates and subsidiaries (“ARIIX”) are committed to respecting your privacy. We’ve structured our Web site so that you can visit ARIIX on the Web without identifying yourself or revealing any personal information. Once you choose to provide us personally identifiable information (any information by which you can be identified), you can be assured that it will only be used to support your customer relationship with ARIIX or your business relationship as an ARIIX Representative (“Representative”).

1\. AWARENESS.  
ARIIX provides this Privacy & Data Protection Policy (this “Policy”) to provide transparency into our practices, ensure fairness and accountability in our data processing and help you exercise your data privacy rights. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available on the bottom of every page on our Web site.

2\. WHAT WE COLLECT AND WHY. 

2.1 Visitors. Upon logging onto our Web server, our Web server automatically recognizes your domain name but not your E-mail address (where possible). We will collect the domain name from which you log on, aggregate information on what pages you access or visit, user-specific information on what pages you access or visit and information volunteered by you (such as survey information and/or site registrations). We do not collect your E-mail address unless you contact us by E-mail or volunteer your E-mail address and other personal information.  
ARIIX websites use “cookies” (tiny text files stored on your hard disk by a web page server) for session management purposes. Cookies cannot harm your computer and they do not contain any personally identifiable information. One of the primary purposes of cookies is to store your preferences and other information on your computer to save you time by eliminating the need to repeatedly enter the same information and to display your personalized content on your later visits to websites. Cookies also help us to improve our site and to deliver a better and more personalized service. Among other things, they enable us:

To estimate our audience size and usage pattern.  
To store information about your preferences, so we can tailor our site to your individual interests.  
To increase the speed of your searches.  
To recognize you when you return to our site.

2.2 Customers. The types of personal information that we collect from customers are limited to: name, address, phone number, email address, payment information and, where legally required, government ID and birth date. This information is required to perform the contractual obligations associated with product orders. Specifically, it enables us to fulfill and ship orders, communicate regarding orders and collect payment for orders.

2.3 Representatives. The types of personal information that we collect from Representatives are limited to: name, birth date, government ID number, address, email address, phone number, bank account and routing number and payment information. (For French Representatives, we also collect country of birth, department of birth, country of residence and Siret number.) This information is required to perform the contractual obligations of our business relationship. Specifically, it enables us to pay commissions, collect payment, fulfill and ship orders, send tax documents and provide business support materials. (For details of those contractual terms, please review our Statement of Policies & Procedures for Representatives and our New Member Agreement.) Another basis for collecting government ID is to fulfill our tax reporting obligations under the laws of your jurisdiction.  
To tailor our communications to you and continuously improve our products and services, we may also ask you to voluntarily provide us with information regarding your personal or professional interests, demographics, experience with our products and contact preferences. Your decision not to provide such information will not affect your ability to continue to order product or receive customer support.

3\. HOW WE USE PERSONAL DATA.  
ARIIX uses your information to perform its contractual obligations to you, meet our legal obligations to the government of your jurisdiction, better understand your needs and provide you with better service. Specifically, we use your information to help you complete a transaction, ship your orders, communicate with you, update you on services and benefits and personalize our Web sites for you. Credit card and bank account numbers are used only for payment and commission processing. We use industry-standard practices to protect this information. For example, credit card numbers provided to us are stored in a tokenized format.

4\. WHOM WE SHARE IT WITH AND WHY.  
ARIIX will not sell, rent or lease your personally identifiable information to others unless we have your permission. We will only share the personal data you provide online with other ARIIX entities and/or business partners who are acting on our behalf. Such ARIIX entities and/or business partners, including those in the United States and/or any other countries, are governed by our privacy policies with respect to the use of this data and are bound by the appropriate confidentiality agreements.  
We share personal data with these third-party business partners to fulfill our contractual obligations to our Representatives, customers and employees. Specifically, we share your information with payment processing companies to collect payment; banks to facilitate commission payments; logistics companies to fulfill and deliver orders; a third-party email service to efficiently send business support materials, including product updates and promotions (from which you may easily unsubscribe at any time); a data archive service to backup data; payroll processing and pension plan companies (only for ARIIX employees); a wholesale travel company for ARIIX Travel users; and an app developer for ARIIX Opportunity Rewards (read-only access).

5\. CHOICE.  
As previously stated, we will also provide you the opportunity to unsubscribe (or otherwise easily opt out) if you do not wish to receive direct marketing materials from us. Following such a request, we will no longer process your personal data for such purposes. Your permission is always secured first, should we ever share your information with third parties that are not acting on our behalf.

6\. RIGHT TO ACCESS, RECTIFY, ERASE AND RESTRICT DATA.  
ARIIX strives to keep your personally identifiable information accurate and secure. You have the right to know what information we hold about you and why. To request this information, or to update, rectify, complete, erase or restrict your information with ARIIX, it will be necessary for you to contact the ARIIX legal department directly at legal@ariix.com. To protect your privacy and security, upon contacting us we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting you access or enabling you to make corrections.  
You may also request confirmation as to whether or not your personal data is processed by ARIIX and, if so, the categories of personal data concerned, the purposes of the processing, the recipients or categories of recipients to whom your data has been or will be disclosed, the anticipated length of time for which your data will be stores, safeguards used pursuant to cross-border data transfers and a copy of the personal data undergoing processing.

Where rectification, restriction or erasure of personal data has been granted, ARIIX will communicate such changes to each third-party recipient to whom such data was previously disclosed and is still necessary, unless this proves impossible or involves disproportionate effort.

7\. RESPONSE TO REQUESTS.  
ARIIX will respond to requests made under the previous section without undue delay and in any event within one month of receipt of the request unless the request is complex or a high number of requests have been made, in which case ARIIX will notify you after one month that up to one additional month may be necessary. The reason for the delay will also be communicated at that time.

8\. SECURITY.  
We take reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information we collect about you remains accurate and secure. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure and while we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee or warrant its complete security. We shall not be responsible for harm that you or any person may suffer due to a breach of confidentiality in respect to your use of the Site or any information you transmit to the Site. To prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the appropriate use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. We industry-standard encryption technology when collecting or transferring sensitive data, such as credit card and bank account information.

9\. DATA TRANSFERRED TO THE U.S.  
We transfer your personal data to our secure, PCI-compliant data center near our headquarters in the U.S. This transfer is necessary for us to process commissions, collect payment, fulfill and ship orders, perform compliance activities, disseminate product and business materials and meet our other contractual obligations to our Representatives and customers. U.S. law may not provide the degree of protection for information that is available in other countries. Should you desire more detailed information regarding data transfers to the U.S., please email our legal department at legal@ariix.com.

10\. FUTURE DEVELOPMENTS.  
If our information practices change at some time in the future, we will first post the policy changes to our Web site to notify you of these changes and the lawful basis of our processing activites. If you are concerned about how your information is used, you should periodically check at the current version of this Policy on our Web site periodically. By using our site, you acknowledge acceptance of the version of this Policy in effect at the time of use.

11\. PROTECTION OF CHILDREN’S PRIVACY.  
We take special care to protect the privacy needs of children. Our Site does not target and is not intended for children under the age of 18, and we will not knowingly collect personal information from them. You must be at least 18 years old to be a customer or Representative.

12\. DATA RETENTION.  
Personally-identifiable information will be kept in active files or systems as long as needed to meet the purposes for which it was collected or as required to perform the contractual relationship with the Representative and his/her up-line, the commercial relationship with the Customer and our legal obligations.ARIIX will make reasonable efforts to ensure that the information is accurate and complete.

13\. THIRD PARTY LINKS.  
ARIIX may at times provide links to other websites. These sites are not controlled by ARIIX and we are not responsible for any content contained on any such website. While we try to link only to sites that share our high standards and respect for privacy, ARIIX is not responsible for the privacy practices employed by other sites. We recommend that you review the privacy and security policies of each website you visit.

14\. COMPLAINTS AND OBJECTIONS.  
ARIIX holds itself accountable to this Policy. We welcome inquiries, concerns, complaints, and objections via the contact method listed in the following section and will respond promptly and work in good faith to resolve them in a fair manner. In addition, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority.

15\. Contact Us.  
Please direct all communications regarding this Policy to the ARIIX legal department via email at legal@ariix.com.
